A Guide to the Papers of Henry Heth, 1765-1800
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Henry Heth 1765-1800
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
38-114
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was deposited in 1932 by Charles R. Kennon. It was made a gift to the Library on December 16, 1980, by Charles R. Kennon, Jr., and Richard R. Kennon of Powhatan, Virginia.
Scope and Content
These manuscripts are principally the business papers of Major Henry Heth (d.1822), Revolutionary soldier, merchant of Richmond and Manchester, and prominent member of the Federalist party.
Harry Heth, as he signed himself, emigrated from England to Virginia in 1759, settled in Chesterfield County, and engaged in various business and commercial enterprises in and around Richmond, and in Norfolk, until his death in 1822. During the Revolution he served first as captain and later as major in the 1st Virginia Regiment, remaining in the service of the state as a militia officer following the close of the war. From 1789 to 1792 he acted as agent for the sale of publicly owned tobacco. His papers record his activities in this connection and as an agent at various times for provisioning United States troops in Virginia. Heth married Nancy Blair, of Richmond, and lived at or near "Black Heath," the home near Manchester of his brother William, and of later generations of this distinguished family, notably Lieut. Gen. Harry Heth of the Confederate army. Some of the papers here calendared reveal details of Heth's operation of the Black Heath coal pits. Others show his association, as a leader of the Federalist party, with George Washington, John Marshall, and important figures in the administration of John Adams. The bulk of the manuscripts, however, fall in the period from 1790 to 1800, are most numerous in the last years of that decade, and relate chiefly to Heth's numerous business interests. The chronological order of the calendar is interrupted by a group of papers, listed together, which record a dispute (1794-95) between Heth and John W. Hunt, his Norfolk partner in a shipping business. Letters from Harry Heth to various governors have been published in the Calendar of Virginia State Papers. His portrait by St. Memin hangs in the Corcoran Art Gallery.
The Heth Papers contain ca. 4,000 items, 1763-1841, and include letters, accounts, bills, receipts, legal documents, and slavery documents. Among the notable items in the collection are: John Marshall, Opinion in the case of Heth v. Cooper and A.L.S. to Harry Heth. (1793 Nov. 8); James Monroe, Indenture appointing Harry Heth attorney to sell land in Bourbon County, Ky. (1812 Mar. 2); John Edmund Page, A.L.S. to Harry Heth (1804 Aug. 12); John Edmund Randolph, A.L.S. to Harry Heth (1811 Apr. 23); Thomas Mann Randolph, nine A.L.S. to Harry Heth. (1813 June 12, 1814 April. 17, 1815 Jul. 22, 1815 Sep. 17, 1815 Oct. 4, 1815 Dec. 4, 1819 Jan. 3). Richmond, Virginia Return of taxable property in the City of Richmond for the year 1788. 22 pp. 1788. Washington, George (1732-1799) A.L.S. to Wm. Heth, et. al. (1799 May 12).
Contents List
- Deed, Charles Ammond to Judith, Elizabeth Jane, and Magdalin Ammond 1765 Jan 2 (Box 1)
- Statement of Jane Amonett 1777 Feb 7 (Box 1)
- Agreement between Jean Ammond, Jn Bransford, Jn Garnett, and Magdalin Amonet 1778 (Box 1)
- Extract from Deed, Lowell to Ronald 1779 Jan 1 (Box 1)
- Indenture 1779 Feb 5 (Box 1)
- Plat of Andrew Donolly's Great Kanhawa River land 1784 Nov 5 (Box 1)
- Agreement between John Stewart and Henry Heth 1786 Jun 22 (Box 1)
- Ephream Houver to Henry Heth 1787 Nov 1 (Box 1)
- James Monroe Indenture 1788 Jan 6 (Box 1)
- Return of taxable property in the city of Richmond for 1788 1788 (Box 1)
- Copy of four receipts of Henry Heth 1788 Jul 31 (Box 1)
- Receipt from John Stewart 1789 Aug 1 (Box 1)
- Execution of collection of debt 1789 Aug 5 (Box 1)
- Letter from Wm. Pennock 1790 Feb 12 (Box 1)
- Bill of sale, Heth from Griffin 1791 Apr 25 (Box 1)
- Account of Henry Heth with Commonwealth of Virginia 1789-1792 (Box 1)
- Account of Henry Heth's sinking fund 1792 Mar 17-Apr 3 (Box 1)
- Order from A. Quaniev 1792 Sep 22 (Box 1)
- Constitution of the Mutual Assurance Society 1792 (Box 1)
- Copy of John Barker's will 1792 Sep 28 (Box 1)
- List of papers to be funded for Heth and Hunt 1793 Feb 14 (Box 1)
- Promise to pay from David Refs 1793 Jun 20 (Box 1)
- Letter from W. O. Callis to Harry Heth 1793 Jun 28 (Box 1)
- Promissory note 1794 Apr 19 (Box 1)
- Letter from Judith Giles to Harry Heth 1794 Jul 14 (Box 1)
- Unidentified 1794-1795 (Box 1)
- Henry Heth's statement concerning claim against him by John W. Hunt and related papers 1794-1795 (Box 1)
- Agreement between Harry Hill and Robert Douthart 1795 Apr 1 (Box 1)
- Order from Alice Quavier 1795 Jun 16 (Box 1)
- Account of sale of L. Rowland's property 1795 Jun 20 (Box 1)
- Young short's will 1795 Sep 7 (Box 1)
- Letter from Francis Bull to Mr. Holmes 1795 Oct 14 (Box 1)
- JM, opinion on method of securing a debt 1795 Nov 9 (Box 1)
- Account, William Bentley with Heth and Stewart 1795 (Box 1)
- Account, Henry Heth with Robert Doothat 1795-1798 (Box 1)
- Obligations of Harry Hill, John Stewart, and Harry Banks to W. Bentley 1796 Feb 9 (Box 1)
- Receipt from Robert Douthat 1796 Feb 17 (Box 1)
- Note from Hardin Burnley 1796 Aug 6 (Box 1)
- Receipt for payment of fire insurance 1796 Oct 1 (Box 1)
- Correspondence between Heth and Stewart and Robert Anderson, hire and sale of slaves 1796 Dec 25 (Box 1)
- Account, William Bentley with Heth and Stewart 1796 (Box 1)
- Account, William Ball with Harry Heth 1796-1798 (Box 1)
- Letters concerning debt of W. Clairborne to A. Cardozo 1797 Feb 16 (Box 1)
- Agreement, A. Cardozo with Harry Heth 1797 Feb 20 (Box 1)
- Harry Heth's agreement to pay 110 pounds to Robert Anderson 1797 Mar 10 (Box 1)
- Debt owed to John Swann 1797 Mar 22 (Box 1)
- Account, Reubin Winfrey with D. Weiriger 1797 Jul 1 (Box 1)
- Letter from Samuel Mosby to Harry Heth 1797 Sep 25 (Box 1)
- Account, George Mays with Harry Heth 1797 Dec 18 (Box 1)
- Account, William Bentley with Harry Heth 1797 (Box 1)
- Account, Haley Cole with Harry Heth 1797 (Box 1)
- Account, Harry Heth with George Watt 1797-1798 (Box 1)
- Account, Thomas White with Harry Heth 1797-1798 (Box 1)
- Account, Wyehoff with Harry Heth 1797-1798 (Box 1)
- Account with Harry Heth 1797-1798 (Box 1)
- Promissory Note, Robertson and Heth to Robert Pollard 1798 Jan 16 (Box 1)
- Debt obligation, Henry Heth and William Dabney to William Allen 1798 Jan 21 (Box 1)
- Account, Robert Anderson with Harry Heth 1798 Apr 24 (Box 1)
- Letter from William Heth to Gen. Washington 1798 Jul 30 (Box 1)
- Account, Harry Heth with Miles Bott 1798 (Box 1)
- Account, Harry Heth with Miles Bott 1798 (Box 1)
- Account, Henry Adams with Harry Heth 1798 (Box 1)
- Account, Miles Ball with Harry Heth 1798-1799 (Box 1)
- Account, William Bentley with Harry Heth 1798-1799 (Box 1)
- Letter from John Harris, Jr. to Harry Heth 1799 Feb 18 (Box 1)
- Letter from J. Wychoft to Harry Heth 1799 Mar 21 (Box 1)
- George Washington to William Heath [sic] 1799 May 12 (Box 1)
- Account 1799 Jul (Box 1)
- Letter from Henry Banks to Harry Heth 1799 Dec 11 (Box 1)
- Letter from Harry Heth to C. Harrison 1799 Sep 26 (Box 1)
- Pollard vs Heth 1799 Oct 21 (Box 1)
- Bond, Beale to O'Hara 1799 Dec 5 (Box 1)
- Account, James Perry to Thompson Blunt, Sr. 1799-1800 (Box 1)
- Account, Harry Heth with T. Blunt 1799-1801 (Box 1)
- Agreement by James Ping to manage Black Heath Pits 1800 Jan (Box 1)
- Letter from George Plumsted to Harry Heth 1800 Jan 5 (Box 1)
- Bond, Rogers to O'Hara 1800 Jan 5 (Box 1)
- Letter from Samuel Marshall to Harry Heth 1800 Jan 6 (Box 1)
- Letter from Robert Burton to Harry Heth 1800 Jan 11 (Box 1)
- Letter from Samuel Marshall to Harry Heth 1800 Jan 11 (Box 1)
- Note Valantine Holdenfate to Harry Heth 1800 Jan 18 (Box 1)
- Letter from Samuel Mifraw to Harry Heth 1800 Jan 18 (Box 1)
- Letter from Henry Banks to Harry Heth 1800 Jan 20 (Box 1)
- Letter from Charles Duncan to Harry Heth 1800 Jan 20 (Box 1)
- Letter from William Rogers to Harry Heth 1800 Jan 24 (Box 1)
- Letter from William King to Harry Heth 1800 Jan 25 (Box 1)
- Letter from Richard Clairborne to Harry Heth 1800 Jan 30 (Box 1)
- Account of U.S. government with Samuel Marshall 1800 Jan-Feb (Box 1)
- Letter from Henry Banks to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 1 (Box 1)
- Letter from A. Davis to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 4 (Box 1)
- Letter from James Baylor to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 6 (Box 1)
- Letter from Joseph Tidbale to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 7 (Box 1)
- Letter from William Rogers to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 8 (Box 1)
- Letter from John Pierce to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 9 (Box 1)
- Letter from Edin Randolph to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 10 (Box 1)
- Letter from D. M. Randolph to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 10 (Box 1)
- Letter from J. Cole to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 10 (Box 1)
- Letter from James-Hayes to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 11 (Box 1)
- Letter from Robert Nicholson 1800 Feb 14 (Box 1)
- Letter from B. Barrand to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 17 (Box 1)
- Letter from Otway Byrd to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 18 (Box 1)
- Agreement between Harry Heth and John Cundiffe 1800 Feb 18 (Box 1)
- Letter from John Cundiffe to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 24 (Box 1)
- Letter from J. R. Read to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 26 (Box 1)
- Letter from John Cundiffe to Harry Heth 1800 Feb 27 (Box 1)
- Letter from John Patten to Harry Heth 1800 Mar 10 (Box 1)
- Letter from Samuel Marshall to Harry Heth 1800 Mar 12 (Box 1)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Rogers 1800 Mar 12 (Box 1)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Heth 1800 Mar 12 (Box 1)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Cundiffe 1800 Mar 13 (Box 1)
- Letters between Henry Heth and Martin Raily 1800 Mar 14-17 (Box 1)
- Harry Heth's coal accounts for March, 1800 1800 Mar 24 (Box 1)
- Letter from Richard Bowler 1800 Mar 29 (Box 1)
- Letter from Vern Bennett to Henry Heth 1800 Mar [29] (Box 1)
- Letter from Vern Bennett to Henry Heth 1800 Mar 31 (Box 1)
- Letter from William Blue to Henry Heth 1800 Apr 2 (Box 1)
- Letter from Samuel Marshall to Henry Heth 1800 Apr 13 (Box 1)
- Letter from William Dabney to Henry Heth 1800 Apr 15 (Box 1)
- Letter to Henry Heth from William Heth 1800 Apr 15 (Box 1)
- William Allen vs. Harry Heth 1800 Apr 16 (Box 1)
- Letter to Harry Heth from R. Gample 1800 Apr 18 (Box 1)
- Receipts 1800 Apr 18 (Box 1)
- Letter to Robert Heth from Robert Gwathmey 1800 Apr 28 (Box 1)
- Account of the United States 1800 Apr 30 (Box 1)
- Letter to Harry Heth from George Plumsted 1800 May 11 (Box 1)
- Receipt from Owen Franklin 1800 May 14 (Box 1)
- Account, Harry Heth with James Strange 1800 (Box 1)
- Letter to Harry Heth from James Cary 1800 May 15 (Box 1)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Browne 1800 May 26 (Box 1)
- Order, Armistead on Heth 1800 May 28 (Box 1)
- Accounts for rations for June 1800 1800 Jun (Box 1)
- Pollard vs Heth 1800 Jun 6 (Box 1)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Benjamin Heth 1800 Jun 6 (Box 1)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Ferdinand Clairborne 1800 Jun 8 (Box 1)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Major Ford 1800 Jun 10 (Box 1)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Samuel and Miers Fisher 1800 Jun 11 (Box 1)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John B. Armistead 1800 Jun 11 (Box 1)
- Accounts for rations 1800 Jun 14 (Box 1)
- Letter to Harry Heth from George Plumsted 1800 Jun 14 (Box 2)
- Letter from Jaynes Bayton to Harry Heth 1800 Jun 16 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William M. Heth 1800 Jun 18 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Robert Goode 1800 Jun 23 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Huskell 1800 Jun 26 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Armistead 1800 Jun 30 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Henry Thompson 1800 Jul 3 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Wychoff and Lyndame 1800 Jul 4 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Horatio Stark 1800 Jul 14 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Vincent Gray 1800 Jul 14 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Robert C. Jennings 1800 Jul 15 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Harkile 1800 Jul 17 (Box 2)
- Letter from William Rogers to Harry Heth 1800 Jul 17 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Jacob Call 1800 Jul 19 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from 1800 Jul 21 (Box 2)
- Two letters to Harry Heth from William Bently 1800 Jul 22 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Vaughan 1800 Jul 23 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from P. Aylett 1800 Jul 24 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Henry Latrobe 1800 Jul 26 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Frazer 1800 Jul 30 (Box 2)
- Letter from William Bentley to Harry Heth 1800 Aug 1 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John B. Armistian 1800 Aug 3 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Thomas R. Roots 1800 Aug 3 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Jesse Cole 1800 Aug 4 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Robert Cary Jennings 1800 Aug 5 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Heth 1800 Aug 7 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Heth 1800 Aug 7 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Easly 1800 Aug 8 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from George Taylor 1800 Aug 9 (Box 2)
- Agreement between Harry Heth and George Beane 1800 Aug 18 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Fielding Lewis 1800 Aug 21 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Davidson 1800 Aug 23 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Frazer 1800 Aug 29 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from M. Gordon 1800 Sep 5 (Box 2)
- Copy of letter from Harry Heth to Secretary of War 1800 Oct 12 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Davidson 1800 Nov 23 (Box 2)
- Accounts of Harry Heth with John Cundiffe 1800 (Box 2)
- Account book 1800 (Box 2)
- Account, William Bently with Harry Heth 1800 (Box 2)
- Memos to accounts 1800-1801 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Rogers 1801 Jan 9 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Alex Mc Donald 1801 Jan 23 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Stewart 1801 Feb 13 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Richard Crump 1801 Feb 17 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from James Tubball 1801 Feb 18 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Robert Brooke 1801 Feb 22 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Thomas B. Armistead 1801 Mar 10 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Kimbrough 1801 Mar 16 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William A. Rogers 1801 Mar 17 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Kimbrough 1801 Mar 24 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Martin Railey 1801 Apr 8 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Paul Trabill 1801 Mar 21 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Kimbrough 1801 Apr 8 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Jo. Heth 1801 Apr 13 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Bentley 1801 Apr 29 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Henry Banks 1801 May 2 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Kimbrough 1801 May 23 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Kimbrough 1801 Jun 3 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from J. Heth 1801 Jun 10 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Kimbrough 1801 Jun 12 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Kimbrough 1801 Jun 12 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from David Woodfin 1801 Jun 15 (Box 2)
- Letter from John Graham to Harry Heth 1801 Jul 4 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Lawrence Muse 1801 Jul 6 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Kimbrough 1801 Jul 7 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from J. Heth 1801 Jul 16 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Kimbrough 1801 Jul 17 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Allen Scruggs 1801 Jul 21 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Fitzhugh 1801 Jul 31 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Horatio Stark 1801 Aug 7 (Box 2)
- Phi Turpin to Henry Heth 1801 Aug 11 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from James Scott, Sr. 1801 Aug 14 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Simmons (see back of page for insert) 1801 Aug 17 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Heth 1801 Sep 24 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Heth 1801 Sep 25 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Robert Gamble 1801 Oct 9 (Box 2)
- Jas. Moir to Harry Heth 1801 Oct 13 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Alexander Spotswood 1801 Oct 14 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Davidson 1801 Oct 16 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Davidson 1801 Oct 19 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Davidson 1801 Oct 22 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Davidson 1801 Nov 3 (Box 2)
- Letter to Daniel Weisigar from J. G. Penniston 1801 Nov 3 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from George Thomsted 1801 Nov 5 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Swann 1801 Nov 6 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from David Lummis 1801 Nov 7 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Stewart 1801 Nov 13 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Stewart 1801 Nov 16 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from George Plumsted 1801 Nov 19 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Robert Gamble 1801 Nov 20 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Davidson 1801 Nov 26 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Benoford and Hobion 1801 Nov 29 (Box 2)
- Letter to Mr. Michaels from Harry Heth 1801 Dec 1 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Davidson 1801 Dec 2 (Box 2)
- Letter from Harry Heth to M Mr. Michaels 1801 Nov 11 (Box 2)
- Accounts and receipts for 1801 1801 (Box 2)
- Agreement between Harry Heth and Andrew Nicolson 1802 Jan 1 (Box 2)
- Statement of William Paterson 1802 Feb 25 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Rogers 1802 Mar 29 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from A. Nicolson 1802 Apr 17 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Davidson 1802 Apr 25 (Box 2)
- Copy of letter from Harry Heth to Thomas Wooland 1802 Aug 3 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Thomas Wooldridge 1802 Aug 7 (Box 2)
- Fire insurance policies of Mr. George Smith 1802 Aug 8 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Martin Railey 1802 Aug 7 (Box 2)
- Letter to Larnia Heth from Caroline T. Pleasants 1802 Nov 12 (Box 2)
- Accounts and receipts for 1802 1802 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Robert Brooke 1803 Jan 12 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from George Hay 1803 Jan 30 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John P. Pleasant 1803 Feb 16 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from A. Nicolson 1803 Feb 26 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from David Paterson 1803 Mar 2 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Davidson 1803 Mar 4 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Joseph Tidball 1803 Mar 9 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Heth 1803 Mar 25 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from George Hay 1803 Mar 26 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from W. Bently 1803 Mar 30 (Box 2)
- Letter from Harry Heth to Mr. Smith Blakey 1803 Apr 13 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from A. Nicolson 1803 Jun 18 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Heth 1803 Jun 23 (Box 2)
- Letters, Miles Seldon to ? 1803 Jun (Box 2)
- Letter from John Royster to John Williams 1803 Jul 5 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Stewart 1803 Jul 21 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from A. Nicolson 1803 Jul 21 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from W. Likhush 1803 Jul 24 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from D. M. Randolph 1803 Jul 24 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from David Paterson 1803 Jul 27 (Box 2)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Marshall 1803 Jul 8 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from A. Nicolson 1803 Jul 27 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Thomas Tredway 1803 Aug 5 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from J. Heth 1803 Aug 22 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Robert Perkins 1803 Aug 23 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from D. M. Randolph 1803 Aug 28 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from S. Pankey 1803 Aug 30 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Davidson 1803 Sep 5 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from George Watson 1803 Sep 8 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Julius Cramps 1803 Sep 13 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Joseph Cooper 1803 Sep 20 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Harold Turpin 1803 Sep 25 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Stewart 1803 Nov 3 (Box 3)
- Letter to John Heth from Harry Heth 1803 Nov 9 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Bushrod Washington 1803 Nov 12 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Samuel Hopkins 1803 Nov 19 (Box 3)
- Deed, Daniel Weisiger to Harry Heth 1803 Nov 22 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Henry Thompson 1803 Dec 17 (Box 3)
- Accounts and receipts for 1803 1803 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from J. Bowis 1804 Jan (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Asa Bishop 1804 Jan 7 (Box 3)
- Articles of co-partnership between Harry Heth and Andrew Nicolson 1804 Jan 1 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Christopher Tompkins [1804 Jan 3] (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Nal. Gordon 1804 Jan 12 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Tayloe 1804 Jan 16 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from A. Nicolson 1804 Jan 19 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Wile Dan Claiborne 1804 Jan 22 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from D. T. Winston 1804 Jan 22 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Peter Nelson 1804 Jan 28 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from H. Turpin 1804 Jan 29 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Henry Banks 1804 Feb 3 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Henry Banks 1804 Feb 12 (Box 3)
- Letter to Nicolson & Heth from Julius Crump 1804 Feb 15 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from David Patterson 1804 Feb 16 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Sale 1804 Mar 1 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Bushrod Washington 1804 Mar 6 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Julius Cramp 1804 Mar 12 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Henry L. Biscoe 1804 Mar 28 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Stewart 1804 Mar 30 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Robinson 1804 Apr 8 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Miles Tilden 1804 Apr 10 (Box 3)
- Letter to Heth & Nicolson from David Ross 1804 Apr 11 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Robert Mimms 1804 Apr 11 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Davidson 1804 Apr 20 (Box 3)
- Letter to [Harry Heth] from A. Nicolson 1804 Apr 21 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from James Scott 1804 Apr 26 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Miles Seldon 1804 Apr 26 (Box 3)
- Letter from John P. Pleasants to Harry Heth 1804 Apr 27 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from George Smith 1804 May 6 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from George Smith 1804 May 19 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Joseph Tidball 1804 May 19 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Robert Perkins 1804 May 22 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from James Scott [1804 May 31] (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from James Scott [1804 May 31] (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Philip Norborne Nickolas 1804 May 31 (Box 3)
- Letter to [Harry Heth] from Peter Nelson 1804 Jul 10 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Nat Gordon 1804 Aug 2 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Ball 1804 Aug 6 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from William Randolph 1804 Aug 10 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from John Page 1804 Aug 12 (Box 3)
- Letter to [Harry Heth] from Miles Selven [1804 Sep] (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Peter Nelson 1804 Oct 21 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from David Petterson 1804 Sep 21 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from A. Nicolson 1804 Sep 22 (Box 3)
- Letter to A. Nicolson from P. Rikin 1804 Sep 26 (Box 3)
- Bond, Harry Heth to William Forse 1804 Sep 29 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from James Scott [1804 Nov] (Box 3)
- Letter to W. H. Heth from John P. Pleasants 1804 Nov 1 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from H. Heth 1804 Nov 5 (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Hervey Heth 1804 Nov 15 (Box 3)
- Letter to [Harry Heth] from A. Nicolson 1804 Nov 16 (Box 3)
- Letter to [Harry Heth] from D. Randolph 1804 Nov 21 (Box 3)
- Articles of co-partnership between John Swann, Harry Heth, and Sam Swann [1804 Nov 27] (Box 3)
- Letter to Harry Heth from Miles Selven 1804 Dec 4 (Box 3)
- Letter to [Harry Heth] from Peter Nelson 1804 Dec 7 (Box 3)
- Letter to [Harry Heth] from David Patterns 1804 Dec 8 (Box 3)